Guide to the Morris Raphael Cohen Papers 1898-1981
University of Chicago Library
- Series II: Writings by Cohen and Students' Papers, 1898-1938
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - "Prolegomena to Logic," 1943, typescript draft (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - "Prolegomena to Logic," Section III; "Abstractions"; IV; "Construction and Hypotheses"; VI; "The Philosophic Significance of Probability"; "Probability and Pure Mathematics"; VII; Values, Norms and Science," typescript draft (Box 27, Folder 7-8)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous notes, "Proof, Confirmation and Verification," notes (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous notes, notes (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous notes, "Logic and Linguistics," notes (Box 27, Folder 13-4)
  - Miscellaneous notes, "Hermeneutics," notes (Box 27, Folder 15-6)
  - Miscellaneous notes, typescript drafts on "Probability" and notes (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous notes, typescript drafts on "Implication" and notes (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous notes, typescript drafts on "Possibility" and notes (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous notes, "Implication and Meaning," typescript drafts and notes (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous notes, "The Presupposition of Logic," typescript draft and notes (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous notes, notes on Psychological Logic and Linguistics (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous notes, notes on "Probability" (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous notes, "On Logic," typescript draft (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - "The Philosophic Significance of Probability," lecture read before the American Philosophical Association, 1935, typescript draft (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Notes on Probability and Determinism (Box 28, Folder 10-15)
  - "Preface to Prologomena to Logic," typescript draft and notes (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - "Meaning and Implication," typescript draft (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - "Meaning and Implication," notes (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - "Fictions," typescript draft (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - "The Philosophic Significance of Probability," lecture read at the Meeting of the American Philosophical Association, 1935, typescript draft (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - "Mathematical Probability," typescript draft (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - "The Statistical View of Nature," typescript draft (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - "Values, Norms, and Science," typescript draft (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - "The Nature of Logic," typescript draft (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - "The Collected Papers of Charles Sanders Peirce, by Charles Hartshorne and Paul Weiss, eds., 1932" book review, typescript draft (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - "Scientific Method in the Social Sciences," typescript draft (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - "On Logic," typescript draft (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - "Notes on the Foundations of Logic," typescript draft (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Notes on Logic (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - "Inadequate Evidence," holograph draft (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Introduction to Logic, miscellaneous notes (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Introduction to Logic, outline and notes (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - "Words and Thought," and other miscellaneous notes on Logic (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - "Hermeneutics," and other miscellaneous notes on Logic (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - "Metaphysics and Logic," notes (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Logic and Scientific Method, outline and notes (Box 29, Folder 12-3)
  - "Syllogism" and other miscellaneous notes (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - "Mill's Method and Formal Logic," typescript draft (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - "Induction and Deduction," notes (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - "The Will to Illusion," typescript draft (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - "The Will to Illusion," notes (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - "The Illusions of Altruism," typescript draft (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - "Illusion is not Error," typescript draft (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - "Dialectics and Truth," draft (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - "The Fundamental Concepts of Science; Extension, Number, Induction, and Substance," typescript draft (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - "Note on Things," typescript draft and notes (Box 29, Folder 23)
  - "On the Nature of Existence," typescript draft and notes (Box 29, Folder 24)
  - "Essence," typescript draft and notes (Box 29, Folder 25)
  - "Individuality," notes (Box 29, Folder 26)
  - "Existence," miscellaneous notes (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - "Metaphysics," miscellaneous notes (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - "What is Meant by the Total Universe," and other typescript drafts (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - "Preface," and other typescript sections of text on Metaphysics (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - "Verification and Probability in Metaphysics," draft (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - "Theory of Cognition," miscellaneous notes (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - "The Concept of Question" and other miscellaneous notes (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - "Polarities," typescript draft (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - "Metaphysics," notes (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - "Metaphysics and Reason," notes (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - "A Priori," notes (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - "Things," notes (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - "Notes on Having an Objective Existence," notes (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - "Only Substances Changes," and other notes on Metaphysics (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - "What is Philosophy," and other notes on Metaphysics (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - "The Nature of Knowledge," draft (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - "Common Fallacies and Popular Discussions of Philosophy," and "Ontologie," [sic], notes (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - "On Meaning," notes (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - "Experience and Reality," typescript notes (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - "Experience and Reality," typescript draft (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - "Origin and Growth of Primitive Religion, the Myth," notes (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - "Religion," notes (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - "Spirituality," notes (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - "Providence and Design in Human Affairs," notes (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - "Religion," typescript draft and notes (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - "How does God Allow Imperfect Beings to Exist?," draft (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - "Aristotle's Classification of the Sciences," typescript draft (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - "The Conditions of Scientific Progress," typescript draft (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - "Einstein's Theory of Relativity," typescript draft (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - "Myth and Science in Popular Philosophy," holograph draft and typescript draft (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - "Method of Science," typescript draft (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - "Philosophy - Definition and Scope," typescript draft (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - "The New Realism," typescript draft (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - "Syllabus of Eight Lectures on the Relations between Philosophy and the Social Sciences," typescript draft (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - "What is the History of Science?" typescript draft (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - "On Scientific Method and System," notes (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - "On Scientific Method," typescript draft (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - "Method of Science," typescript draft (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - "Origin of Conception of Number," notes (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - "Mathematics and Philosophy," outline (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - "Astronomy and Copernicus," notes (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - "Theory that Greek Science Failed," and other miscellaneous notes (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - "Report of Seminar held 23rd March, 1939 Under Secretary Wilson's Office, 9 A.M.," transcript of conversation between Blaisdell, Schwarz, Cohen, Tuckerman, Wilcox, etc. (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - "Padua and Modern Science," notes (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - "Philosophy," misc. notes (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - "The Problem of Language," miscellaneous notes (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - "Causality," typescript draft (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - "On the Laws of Nature," typescript draft (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - "Logic and Psychology," notes (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - "Parminides Theory of Cognition," draft and notes (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - "Psychology and Behaviorism," notes (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - "Psychology as a Natural Science," typescript draft and notes (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - "Psychology," notes (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - "Rational Psychology," typescript draft (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - "Characterology," notes (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - "Psychology," notes (Box 32, Folder 2-4)
  - "The Unconscious," notes (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - "Stimulus Response," notes (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - "Psychology and Culture," notes (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - "Psychology and Behavior," notes (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - "Reality of Circumstances," notes (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - "Notes on the Self," notes (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - "Transmutation," notes (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Greek science, notes (Box 32, Folder 12-3)
  - "Differences in Flowers, by Theophrastus, translated by Sir Arthur Hort, London 1916," book review, typescript draft (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - "Geometry," notes (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Greek Science, notes (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - "Source Book in Greek and Roman Science," (bibliography), typescript draft (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - "Mathematics," (bibliography), typescript draft (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - "General Physical Description of the Heart," typescript draft (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - "Mathematics," notes (Box 32, Folder 20-1)
  - "Answers and Questions with Regard to the Deduction of the Categories," draft (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - "Kant," notes (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - "Kant's Deduction of the Categories," notes (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - "The Place of Happiness in the Kantian Philosophy," PhD thesis, typescript draft with holography notes and corrections (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - "Kant's Second Analogy," draft (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - "The Paralogisms of Pure Reason," student paper (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - "Kant's Transcendental Aesthetic," student paper (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - "Kant's Ethics," notes (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - "Kant's Philosophy," notes (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - "The Mathematical Antimonies," draft (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Kant and Fichte, notes (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - "Kant's Practical Philosophy," notes (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - "Royce on Kant," notes (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Kant, notes (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - "Kant's Doctrine of the Categories," notes (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - "Romantic Elements in Kant," typescript draft (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Mathematics, notes (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - "Physics," and other miscellaneous notes (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - "Is Space Real?" notes (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - "Einstein," notes (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - "Syllabus of Lectures on Time, Space, and Relativity," notes (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Physical Science, notes (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - "Davidson and Adler," draft (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - "The Concept of the Good in Descartes, Leibniz and Spinoza," draft (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - "A Critique of Anthropocentric Naturalism," typescript draft (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - John Dewey, notes (Box 34, Folder 2-3)
  - "Idealism and Dialectics," notes (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - "Hegel's Rationalism," notes (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - "Hegel," notes (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - "Hegel and Monism," notes (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - "Hegel - Life," notes (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - "Hegel, Naturphilosophie," notes (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - "Hegel, Philosophy of Religion," notes (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - "Hegel, Art," notes (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Hegel, miscellaneous notes (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - "Hegel, Bibliography," notes (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - "Hook's Pragmatism," notes (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - "Rousseau," notes (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - "Spinoza and Liberalism," notes (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - "Spinoza," typescript lecture (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - "Whitehead, May and Sinclair," notes (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - "Ayres," notes (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - "The Confessional in Buddhism," notes (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Notes on Continuity (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - "Education," typescript draft and notes (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - "The Educational Journal," (beginning September 25, 1897) paperbound daily journal on the theme of education (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - Notes on Election (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - "Empiricism," notes (Box 34, Folder 25)
  - "Postscript in Time of War," typescript draft and notes (Box 34, Folder 26)
  - "Faith of a Liberal," typescript draft (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - "Faith of a Liberal," notes (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - "Faith of a Liberal," "Constitutional and Natural Rights in 1789 and Since," typescript draft (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - "Faith of a Liberal," Table of Contents, typescript drafts (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - "Fictions," notes (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - "The Future of American Liberalism," typescript draft (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - "Is War Inevitable?" typescript draft (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - "Mechanism and Purpose," typescript draft of outline (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - "Mysticism and Rationalism," notes (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - "History of Philosophy," typescript draft (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - "Vision and Technique in Philosophy," typescript draft (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - "Vision and Technique in Ethics and in the Philosophy of History," typescript draft (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - "Romantic Philosophers," notes (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Address at the Second Annual Labor Conference, Tamiment Economic and Social Institution, June 1936, typescript draft (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - "Philosophy as Technique," notes (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - "Vision and Technique," notes (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - "Inadequacy of Introspection," notes (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - "From the Physical to the Social Sciences, by Jacques Rueff, 1929," (book review), typescript draft (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - "Industrial Discipline and the Governmental Arts, by Rexford Tugwell, 1993," (book review), typescript draft (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - "Turgenev," (book review of Turgenev, by Avrahm Yarmolinsky, 1926), typescript draft (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - "Law and Reason," 1922, typescript draft (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - "The Birthright of Esau," (book review of The Abolition of Inheritance, by Harlan Read), typescript draft (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - "American Interpretations of Natural Law, by Benjamin Wright, 1931," (book review), typescript draft, and other book reviews (Box 35, Folder 23)
  - "Prologomena to Logic," 1943, typescript draft (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Prologomena to Logic," various chapters, typescript draft (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Prologomena to Logic," with assorted papers on logic (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - "Preface to Logic," 1944, incomplete draft (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - "Nineteenth-century thought," lecture, 1924, typescript notes (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - "Nineteenth-century thought," miscellaneous notes (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - "Eleven lectures on Ninetieth-century Thought," typescript drafts (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - "The Case Against Compulsory Military Science," typescript draft (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - "Questionnaire on Military Science," typescript draft (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - "Studies in Juristic Philosophy," miscellaneous papers (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - "Remarks of Professor Cohen," typescript draft (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Lectures, 1924, transcripts (Box 37, Folder 3-5)
  - Miscellaneous lectures on history, typescripts (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - "Some Thoughts on Troubled Days," holograph draft (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous papers, drafts (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - "Topics for Essays in Philosophy," notes (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - "Notes on the dinner, May 14, 1938," typescript notes (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - "The Progressive Party and the A Priori Spirit," and other papers on law and ethics, typescript draft (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - "The Ruling Class, by Gaetano Mosca," (book review), typescript (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous research notes (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous research notes index cards (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - "Reason and Nature," edited typescript, p. 1-171 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - "Reason and Nature," edited typescript, p. 172-320 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - "Reason and Nature," edited typescript, p. 321-457 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - "Reason and Nature," edited typescript, p.458-595 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - "Philosophy of Science," typescript draft (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - "Scientific Method," typescript drafts (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - "Science and Religion," typescript lecture (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - "Politics and Law," lecture notes (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - "Immortality," lecture notes (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Political science, notes (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - American sculpture, notes (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Influence, notes (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Genius, miscellaneous notes (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Law, miscellaneous notes (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Legal theory, miscellaneous notes (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Papers and Congresses on Philosophy, various individuals (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Reports to the Committee on Scientific Method, various authors (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - American Academy of Jurisprudence, Charter Meeting (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - League for Industrial Democracy, 1931 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Lytton Commission, League of Nations, 1932 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Student exams and papers in Cohen's Philosophy course, 1930s (Box 40, Folder 1-5)
  - Student exams and papers (Abraham Deutsch, J. Douglas, Reuben Fine, A. Flaxer) (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Student exams and papers (Samuel Fooner, Osmond Fraenkel, Benjamin Fuchs) (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Student exams and papers (Morris Garfinkel, Benjamin Ginzburg, Herbert Glantz, Isidor Goldberg, S. Goldfarb) (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Student exams and papers (Knox Hill) (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Student exams and papers (Robert Johnson) (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Student exams and papers (S. Jacobson, M. Horowitz) (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Student exams and papers (Dan Katz, A.J. Klausner, Leon Koss, Shelley Krasnow, M. Langer, Samuel Leibowitz, Harold Leidner) (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Student exams and papers (David Levine, Sidney Liben, Rosamund Law, Max Lichtman, Michael Mackler, Jerome Malino, Robert Marcus) (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Student exams and papers (Robert Marcus, Max Meisel, William Messing) (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Student exams and papers (J.D. Meyer, A.E. Michelson, Helen Mins, Hyman Moskowitz) (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Student exams and papers (Milton Munitz, Joseph Nash, Herman Neuhaus) (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Student exams and papers (Bertha Prerau, Sidney Ratner, Irving Roth, Edward Rosen, Bernard Schein) (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Student exams and papers (Sam Schneider, Charles Segal, Samuel Singer) (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Student exams and papers (Philip Slaner) (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Student exams and papers, (Aaron Solomon, Julia Sonn, Charles Turck, Ben Vogel) (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Student exams and papers (Harold Wein) (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Student exams and papers (Charles Weinstein, Leo Yamin) (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 41, Folder 4-19)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 42, Folder 1-16)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 43, Folder 1-16)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 44, Folder 1-14)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 45, Folder 1-15)
- Series III: Personal Papers, Papers Relating to Thomas Davidson, and Other Papers, 1898-1980
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 46, Folder 1-4)
  - Eulogy for Thomas Davidson (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - "Aristotle and Modern Political Science," typescript draft (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - "Socrates," and "Aeschylus," typescript lectures by Thomas Davidson (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - The Origin of the Breadwinners' College, typescript lecture (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Letters from Thomas Davidson to his class, typescript carbons (Box 46, Folder 9-10)
  - "Aeschylus and his Ethical System," typescript draft (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - "Plato's Treatment of Poetry," and "How Far Plato has answered Aristotle's Objections," notes by Thomas Davidson (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - "Aristotle and Plato," notes by Thomas Davidson (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Letters and announcements related to the Thomas Davidson School (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Biography and bibliography of Thomas Davidson (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - "The Ethical Society as an Educational Institution for Adults," lecture (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - "The Unendurable Tyranny of a Purely Communistic State," galley (Box 47, Folder 1a)
  - "The Higher Education of the Breadwinners," September 1899, typescript lecture, possibly by Davidson (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - "The Higher Work of the Educational Alliance," lecture (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - "The Work of the Thomas Davidson Society," lecture and notes (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Thomas Davidson memorial lectures (Box 47, Folder 4a)
  - "The Work of the Thomas Davidson Society," Branch B, notes and other materials (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - "Aunt B's notes of Morris R. Cohen's `Philosophy of History' course, 1899-1900," notebook (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - "Life of Thomas Davidson," draft, author unknown (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Educational Alliance, notes (Box 47, Folder 8-9)
  - Diaries, #1-5, 1894 -1898 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Diary, 1900-1903, and personal notes (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Personal notes, ca. 1897 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Personal notebook, undated (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Personal notebooks, one marked "Thoughts and Reflections Prior to 1904" (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Harvard job application, letters of recommendation, 1906 (Box 48, Folder 3a)
  - "[Auto]biography of Morris R. Cohen," draft and other notes (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Meetings of the Discipline Committee, 1935-1936 (Box 48, Folder 5-6)
  - On the Censorship of The Campus, typescript record (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - "The Case Against Compulsory Military Science," typescript draft (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations, Minutes of the Board of Directors, March 1935-1939 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations, Minutes of the Board of Directors, 1940; Annual Report of the President, 1940, 1940-1943, 1943-1946 and other reports; "Receipts and Disbursements by Years," 1933-1936; 1936-1936; 1937-1938; 1940, typescript reports (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations, Minutes of the Board of Directors, 1939; Conference on Jewish Relations, Transcript of Meeting, May 16th, 1937, list of publications, and organizational statement (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations, Correspondence and memos, 1937-1945 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations, donor and member lists, 1936 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations, papers and correspondence concerning the "economic life of Jews." (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Book Prospectus, "Jews of New York"; Jewish Social Studies and other materials related to Jewish relations and populations in various cities (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - "Die Judenfrage als Forschungsaufgabe" typescript draft; memos and papers concerning Jewish relations, economic discrimnation, and anti-Semitism (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - "A Jewish Community Library in Chicago," typescript carbon, and other documents related to the establish of Jewish libraries in various cities (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations, Medical Committee on Research, Sub-Committee Report on Approved Residences in Jewish Hospitals, typescript draft (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Conference on Jewish Relations, Report on Madagascar, typescript draft, personal correspondence, clippings and other articles related to Jewish Migration (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Committee on Peace Studies, 1940-1945, various materials (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Aaron Margalith, "The American Use of the Doctrine of Intervention," typescript draft; Moses Moskowitz, "Diplomatic and Political Developments During the First Four Months of the War of Direct or Indirect Interest to Jews," 1940, two typescript drafts; and other materials related to political and social economy (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Meeting of the Program Committee of Lawyers Committee of the Conference on Jewish Relations; Memos, Jewish Occupational Council, and other materials (Box 50, Folder 5)